One, ten, hundred, thousand, ten thousand, one hundred thousand…
个、十、百、千、万、十万…
Amazing! This solid gold watch is sick!
哇！这个纯金的手表太豪横啦！
I never would've made enough to own one
就凭我在那家黑心企业赚的微薄薪水
on my pitiful salary at that exploitative company!
一辈子都买不起这么贵的表！
Oh, man, Akira.
我的天 阿辉
Check this out!
看这个！
One hundred thousand, one million…
十万、百万…
Solid gold…
纯金…
is something.
原来还算便宜啊
15. GET A SOLID GOLD WATCH
（15 弄一块纯金手表）
We're out of water, Kencho.
水箱没水了 阿宪
I figured. The power's out too, and it's pitch black in the city.
毕竟现在停电了 城里一片漆黑
Guess the water pumps gave out when the electricity did.
水泵需要电力才能运作
Base station's down too. I can't get online.
基站的服务也中断了 我连不上网
Our phones are charged, but we can't get any news.
虽然手机还有电 但没法查看新闻
We might be the only people left in this big city.
这偌大的城市里 也许只剩我们两个幸存者了
The number of zombies are increasing daily.
僵尸的数量与日俱增
It's getting more difficult to secure food and water too.
获取食物和饮水也越来越困难
It may be time we start taking this seriously.
我们或许是时候认真起来 为将来做打算了
Food and a safe place to live?
获取食物和寻找安全的住所吗？
Heroes aren't paid in food.
当英雄可赚不来食物
Do we start farming in the country? Or hunt?
我们要去乡下种地吗？或者去打猎？
Can a ramen shop survive in a zombie apocalypse?
在僵尸灾难的洗礼下 开拉面店经营得下去吗？
Even after quitting my abusive workplace, I guess I still have to work.
看来哪怕辞掉了在黑心企业的工作 我还是免不了得干活呀
I wonder if there's any job out there that I'd want to do now.
不知道现在外面 还有没有我想做的工作
Never mind that. Look, Kencho!
不想那个了 你看 阿宪
This is amazing!
星空好美啊
Tokyo's not so bad!
东京还不算太糟嘛
Major power outages aren't all that bad.
大面积断电也不完全是坏事呢
This brings back memories.
这感觉真令人怀念
I'm sure they're alive and safe.
我相信你爸妈一定还平安活着
Yeah!
没错！
Let's head out to my hometown that I haven't seen in a while. To Gunma!
好久没回老家了 我们快出发吧 去群马！
Remember to pack light.
记得要轻装简行哦
I know that!
知道啦！
Water and canned food, toothbrush, nail clipper, camp stove, cook set…
水、罐头食品、牙刷、指甲剪 便于携带的烧水壶、成套厨具…
I can just go to a convenience store when I need a change of underwear, right?
想换内衣裤时 只要随便找家便利店就行了吧？
No, I need to have some ready on the off chance I spend the night with a lady.
不行 还是得随身携带 万一有机会跟美女过夜呢？
That's packing light?
你管那叫轻装简行？
Is that really packing light?
你是认真的吗？
Bye-bye, college life.
再见了 我的大学生涯
Bye-bye, office life.
再见了 职场生活
How far is it to your parents' home?
这儿离你爸妈家有多远？
Normally, it's a three or four hour drive, but I don't know what the roads are like.
通常是三四个小时车程 但我不知道现在的路况如何
It could be long, so there's something I absolutely want to get!
也许要花很长时间 所以我想先去搞一样东西
Are you talking about a real gun?
你是说搞一支真枪吗？
Nope!
不
Equipped with a kitchen and bathroom!
配备有厨房和厕所
A zombie-free space where you don't have to worry!
可以放心休息的无僵尸空间
A best friend for leisurely trips where you can sleep whenever!
休闲旅行最佳伴侣 随时可以睡觉！
A house on wheels, where dreams and a sense of adventure are made!
会行走的房子 梦和冒险开始的地方
An RV is the only way to travel in a zombie apocalypse!
露营车当然是 在僵尸大灾难期间出行的不二选择！
So can we do that? We only live once!
可以吗？人生只有一次
Can we travel in an RV?
我们开露营车旅行好吗？
I think it's a great idea!
我举双手赞成！
RV SHOW
（露营车展）
What?
什么？
Shizuka?
闲？
We sure run into each other a lot.
我们还真是有缘呀
Come to think of it, you did say you were headed out of the city.
话说回来 你之前确实说过要出城
What a coincidence.
好巧呀
I never expected to see you again so soon!
没想到这么快又见到你啦
It happened not just twice, but three times!
这已经不是两次 而是三次巧遇了
This is definitely fate!
绝对是命运的安排！
Since you're here, would you like to go to Gunma with us--
既然遇见了 你要不要跟我们一起去群马…
I don't have enough lives to team up with you.
我没那么多条命来冒险跟你们组队
Since I see no benefit in forming an alliance,
跟你们搭伙对我没好处
thank you for the offer, but I'll have to decline.
感谢邀请 但是我仍然要拒绝
Shizuka, do you have a license?
闲 你有驾照吗？
No. But this is a state of emergency.
没有 但现在是紧急状况
I've come to realize that the best way to travel long distances
必须在远途旅行中规避风险
while avoiding risks would be an RV.
我能想到的最佳方案就是驾驶露营车
You see them in zombie movies sometimes.
有些僵尸片里也是这么演的
I didn't expect you to be a fan of zombie movies.
真看不出来 你居然爱看僵尸片
I'm not. I just watched them for reference purposes.
我不爱看啊 只是作为参考而已
About 100 movies.
大概看了上百部吧
That's hard-core fan territory.
那已经是骨灰级粉丝的境界了
In any case, an RV is the travel standard in a zombie apocalypse.
无论如何 露营车 在僵尸大灾变中都是出行标配
Right? I said the same thing! You really should come with--
是吧？我也是这么说的！ 真心建议你跟我们一起…
Thank you for the offer, but I'll have to decline.
感谢邀请 但是我拒绝
But you don't have a license, right?
但你没有驾照 不是吗？
Exactly.
对呀
Isn't it poor risk analysis to do something unfamiliar like driving?
做自己不擅长的事 比如开车 这会增加风险 不是吗？
I'm sure you can see the benefits of forming an alliance.
我想你肯定能意识到 跟我们结伴的好处吧
But even so…
话虽如此…
It'll definitely be more fun with three people!
三人同行肯定更有趣的！
That has nothing to do with the issue at hand.
这跟当下讨论的问题没关系吧
It'll be safer together with three people!
三个人一起更安全！
Let's go!
一起走吧！
RV SHOW ENTRANCE
（露营车展入口）
-An RV show! Amazing!
-露营车展！好酷啊！
That's so cool!
太酷啦
That's super cool!
酷毙了！
This is crazy! What is this? It's totally crazy!
太帅了！这是什么？超酷炫呀！
Why does it have treads? Why are they triangular?
车轮怎么还有履带呀？ 而且为什么是三角形的呀？
This one has a crane attached!
这辆车还配了起重机！
Oh my god! What do we pull it with? What do we pull it with?
哇！我们用它来拉什么好呀？
Tatami mats!
还有榻榻米！
A Japanese-style room? Is it for tea ceremonies?
日式房间？是用来开茶道会的吗？
How hard is it to do?
您泡的茶真好喝呀
There's a jacuzzi in the car! Wow!
房车里有按摩浴缸！天哪
Taking into account mobility and speed in an emergency,
考虑到在紧急情况下 对灵活性和速度的需求
a four-wheel drive is a must, since it has the greatest maximum output.
必须选择四驱车 因为可达到的输出功率最高
If we're going both on and off-road, a midsize SUV would do the trick.
若要交替在公路或者野地行驶 中型运动休旅车能满足要求
And considering it might be difficult to refuel,
再考虑到加油或许不容易
maybe we should go with a hybrid crossover.
最好选择油电混合动力的跨界车
Furthermore, in terms of durability, perhaps we should go with an import
另外 从耐用性角度出发 考虑到车辆的防撞缓冲区
rather than a domestic one for the crumple zone.
应该选择进口车 而不要本土的
Which means something like this seems about right.
也就是说 像这样的刚刚好
What the hell is this?
这是什么？
Twenty million?
两千万日元？
An RV that costs more than twenty million!
两千多万日元的露营车！
I want this one.
我好想要
I definitely want this one!
决定了 我要这辆！
How is something that big going to get through roads full of abandoned vehicles?
这么大的车怎么在 布满废弃车辆的道路上行驶啊？
We're going with this one. And that's final.
这辆最适合 选这辆 没得商量
What?
什么？
Well, that one is cool, but it doesn't look like an RV at all!
那辆是很帅没错啦 但它看起来一点也不像露营车呀
At all!
完全不像！
It's just a regular car, man!
那就是辆普通的车嘛 拜托！
Man!
拜托！
We should at least pick one that has a roof that pops out and becomes a tent.
我们至少得选一辆 车顶能弹出来当帐篷用的吧
Sleeping under a pop-up roof is like advertising we're zombie food!
在车顶帐篷里睡觉 不就等于邀请僵尸来开餐吗？
Come on now.
好了啦
Life's boring if you only do what you need to do all the time.
一味理智地选择做该做的事 那人生多无趣呀
Shizuka, I bet there's a ride somewhere here that'll get you going.
闲 我敢打赌 这里肯定有能让你一见钟情的车
Honestly, we're in a crisis. Why would I stoop to choosing based on…
真是的 我们正处于危机中耶 我干吗要自甘堕落去根据喜好选…
A coordinated dark color scheme with indirect lighting.
协调的暗黑系色调搭配间接照明设计
A water hyacinth sofa and ikat tapestries.
水风信子藤编沙发和图腾挂毯
What's with this interior? It looks like a luxury hotel in Bali!
这个内部装潢 真像巴厘岛上的豪华酒店！
Oh, no. It's wonderful.
不好 它太完美了
I think I might want it.
我想要搭这辆车
I knew there would be one you wanted!
我就知道这里一定有你喜欢的类型！
No! That one doesn't count!
不！刚才那个不算
Cars are all about dreams and a sense of adventure!
选车就是为了圆自己的梦 和成全冒险精神呀
Safety and utility!
是为了安全和实用性
Oh no! They found us!
不好！僵尸找过来了
We were too loud!
我们刚才太大声了啦
What should we do?
该怎么办？
It doesn't matter which one! Hurry up and get in!
别纠结选哪辆了 先上车再说！
What about the keys?
钥匙怎么办？
It's in the ignition!
钥匙插在车上呢！
Hurry, hurry!
快启动呀
17. RIDE IN AN RV
（17 开露营车）
It's creepy how quiet it is.
太宁静了 感觉好诡异
The highway is usually packed on weekdays.
工作日的高速公路通常很拥堵的
People probably didn't get to run before the infection spread.
也许僵尸病毒散播开的时候 人们还没来得及上路吧
No virus in history has spread this rapidly.
历史上没有任何病毒能传播得这么快
Shizuka, do you think this is a virus?
闲 你觉得这是病毒吗？
Aggression caused by hormonal changes that affect the brain…
荷尔蒙波动影响大脑 从而导致攻击性行为…
The only thing that could do that is most likely a virus.
能做到这些的 大概率就是病毒了
Analyzing data about the outbreak and pinpointing methods of transmission
分析关于这次僵尸爆发的数据 并确认传播途径
can help us work out a possible countermeasure.
有助于我们寻找可能的对策
And there are many other potential solutions.
有很多潜在的解决方案
If we can create a vaccine, we can counter any sort of dangerous virus.
如果能研制出疫苗 就能对抗任何种类的危险病毒
Theoretically, the world isn't over just yet.
理论上说 这个世界还没完蛋
There's still hope.
还是有一线希望的
Does that mean, somewhere out there,
你的意思是 在某个未知的角落
there are people who are working to stop the infection and save the world?
有人正在努力阻止感染 拯救世界吗？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
At the very least, it has nothing to do with those of us who are barely surviving
就算有 那也与我们这些每天 为生存而挣扎、被僵尸追赶的人无关
each day dealing with zombies, does it?
不是吗？
We'll be leaving Saitama soon!
就快离开埼玉县了呢
Gunma's in sight!
群马近在眼前了！
Before we do that, I'm starving!
在那之前 我快饿死了
Let's stop by a truck stop to find something to eat.
我们去服务区找点东西吃吧
It'll be getting dark. We should also rest for the day!
天快黑了 我们也该找个地方休息了
All right! This is our first night in an RV!
好啊！这还是我们 第一次在露营车上过夜呢
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Kencho!
阿宪！
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
What happened?
怎么会这样？
A spike strip?
是钉条？
What?
什么？
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事？
Well, look who it is. If it isn't Tendo.
哟 瞧瞧呀 这不是天道嘛？
What do you think you're doing here, skipping out on work?
你丢下工作 跑到这里来做什么？
You're…
你是…
Chief Kosugi!
小杉领导！
I told you, your deadline was first thing in the morning.
我跟你说了今天一早就是截止日期
Why aren't you done with it, Tendo?
天道 为什么工作还没有完成？
What? But Chief, yesterday you said I had until tonight.
什么？可是领导 您昨天说期限是今晚…
Did I ask for you damn opinion?
我有问你意见吗？
Damn it! You're always creating more work for me.
混蛋！总是给我平添工作量
Are you harassing me? Are you harassing your superior?
你是在存心给我添堵吗？ 成心跟你上司过不去？
If I get depressed, what are you gonna do?
我要是抑郁了 你打算怎么办？
Umm…
什么？
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Cosgies.
这帮人叫…
A baseball team?
Cosgies？
I didn't expect you to survive the apocalypse.
真没想到你有本事 在这次灾难中活到现在啊
Chief, I'm glad to see you're doing well too.
领导 看到你没事 我也很高兴
What's going on?
怎么回事？
My stomach is churning and I can't breathe.
我的胃里翻江倒海 而且不能呼吸了
I see you've gotten yourself into a pretty sticky situation.
我看你现在遇到困难了呀
I doubt you can continue your journey on those tires.
车胎爆了 你们很难继续上路吧？
You should hurry up and tend to your friend.
还得抓紧处理你朋友的伤
Want me to lend you a hand, Tendo?
想要我帮忙吗 天道？
Luckily, our truck stop
算你走运 我们的服务区
is fully stocked with food, spare tires, and medical equipment.
有充足的食物、备用轮胎和医疗器械
We'll change your tires and get your friend patched up.
我们会帮你换轮胎 给你朋友包扎伤口的
Chief.
领导
I'm just so glad to see you again
我真是太高兴了
here at the end of the world.
没想到在世界末日 来临时还能再见到你
You have nothing to worry about anymore.
你什么都不用再担心了
As your old boss, I'd never abandon a former employee.
身为领导 我是绝不会抛下前雇员不管的
Just leave it to me!
放心交给我吧
Chief!
领导！
-Thank-- -However, in exchange, Tendo…
-谢… -不过 作为交换 天道
How would you like to work for me once again?
你愿意再次为我工作吗？
What?
什么？
-But… -I get it now. So, that's your racket.
原来如此 这一切都是你的阴谋
You rob people's mode of transportation with those things,
用那些钉条破坏别人的交通工具
injure and manipulate them when they're helpless,
导致他们受伤 然后乘人之危 操控他们
and then put them to work cheaply.
让他们给你充当廉价劳动力
That's a pretty uncharitable interpretation, little lady.
你这样的解读未免太刻薄了 小姑娘
The laws of the land no longer exist in this world.
现如今 这世间已经成了法外之地
We had no choice but to lay these traps to protect our precious friends
我们别无选择 只能设下陷阱来保护重要的伙伴
from ruthless looters.
免于遭受残忍的劫掠
I hope you understand.
希望你们能理解
You don't have much time.
没多少时间让你犹豫了
All that noise earlier is drawing them here.
刚才的动静已经引来了僵尸
Two days, Tendo!
两天就好 天道
You only have to help us with a few chores for just two days.
你只需要在两天时间里 帮我们干一点杂务
I'm sure you'll work for me again, won't you?
我相信你会愿意 再为我效力的 对吗？
Well…
这个…
But…
可是…
However…
但是…
You don't want your friends to become zombie food, do you?
你也不希望自己的朋友 沦为僵尸的美餐吧？
Very well.
好的
If it's just for two days, I'd be happy to work for you again.
如果只是两天的话 我很乐意再为您效劳
Atta boy!
这就对啦！
We've got ourselves a contract!
那我们就此达成协议喽
KAMISATO EXIT
（上里服务区）
Welcome to my company!
欢迎加入我的公司！
Starting today, you'll be working the loading dock
从今天起 你就负责装卸货物
and reinforcing the barricade.
和加固防线
They're simple jobs that anyone can do.
都是些简单的活计 是个人都能干
It'll be all right.
没事的
I'm sure it'll be difficult since you're inexperienced,
虽然你缺乏经验 一开始会觉得很难
but with the trust that we've cultivated over many years,
但凭借我们在过去几年里 培养出来的信任
you'll quickly regain a feel for things.
我相信你很快就能重新上手的
Okay.
好
FIRST AID
（急救箱）
I don't think you've fractured anything,
应该没有骨折
but you should rest up for the time being.
但目前还是建议你休息静养
Damn it.
可恶
It's my fault Akira's…
都怪我 阿辉才会…
They had this all planned out.
是他们处心积虑设了陷阱
This isn't your fault.
不是你的错
Damn it!
可恶！
If we could just change our tires, we could be out of here!
只要换好轮胎 我们就能离开这里了！
We just have to tolerate this for two days.
熬过这两天就好
I sure hope that's the case.
但愿如此吧
My arms are so swollen!
我的手臂快撑不住了
When is this going to end?
这些箱子什么时候才能搬完啊？
This is just like being back at my old job!
感觉像又重操旧业了一样！
No. That's not what this is.
不 这跟以前不一样
I'm not who I was before.
我已经不是从前的我了
I decided I was finally going to live life my way, right?
我决定了要按照 自己的想法生活 不是吗？
Everyone has been working so hard in this heat.
大热天的 大家还一直这么卖力
Beer! Beer!
啤酒！
If I chill them now, I wonder if they'll be ready by dinner?
现在冰镇起来 到晚饭时间应该够凉了吧？
That'll make everyone happy!
大家一定会很高兴的！
Hey, Tendo!
喂 天道！
Chief.
领导
This isn't your station.
这不是你的工位
What are you doing…
你在干什…
Hey! When did I order you to do that?
喂！我什么时候吩咐你这么干了？
Umm… Uhh…
这…
I was just doing this for everyone.
我只是想帮大家冰一些啤酒
Again? Why?
这感觉怎麽又来了？
When the Chief's in front of me, I can't think straight.
只要领导站在面前 我便无法冷静思考
Giving them chilled beer is just a waste of our precious electricity.
让他们喝冰啤酒 只会浪费我们宝贵的电力
Try something funny like this again and you won't--
下次你要再敢擅作主张 就别想…
What is that, Kosugi?
那是什么 小杉？
It's beer!
是啤酒呀！
What?
什么？
That's not for us, right?
不会是给我们准备的吧？
You always stick us with that warm cheap stuff.
你总让我们喝那种常温的便宜货
Why the change of heart?
怎么忽然改主意了？
Yeah!
是呀！
I just asked Tendo to chill these for you guys tonight.
我刚叫天道把这些啤酒冰镇起来 好让你们今晚喝呢
Of course, there's enough for everyone here.
当然啦 大家人人有份哦
Tonight, we're having a welcome party for Tendo and his friends
今晚我们要为天道 和他的朋友们办一场欢迎会
so you can rest and recuperate from the day.
你们辛苦工作一天 正好休息放松一下
This is just a small gesture of gratitude for all the work you do
小小心意 以示感谢大家日以继夜地
for the company around the clock.
为公司辛勤工作
You're so generous, Kosugi.
你真豪爽 小杉
I'm glad I came with you.
还好我当初跟了你
Cut that out. Flattery will get you nowhere.
别拍马屁了 奉承话可不能当饭吃
What is that?
那是什么？
You're making zombies pull cargo?
居然让僵尸帮你拉货？
They're a good workforce if you know how to use them.
只要掌握了驱使他们的方法 僵尸是绝佳的劳动力
They're company equipment,
他们都是工具
mere equipment with no will of their own, and who can't think for themselves.
没有个人意志 不会为自己打算的工具
They just need to shut up and keep working.
只要闭上嘴 乖乖干活儿就好
Equipment.
工具
And Tendo…
天道
Like them, you're merely equipment as well.
你也只是个工具 跟他们没有分别
It seems like
你似乎认为
you thought you were capable of achieving something special.
你能成就一番非比寻常的事业
But you're far more worthless than you think.
但你比自己以为的要没用得多
The best you can do is to just follow my orders
你最好的选择就是服从我的命令
and try to be as useful as those zombies out there.
尽可能地让自己多发挥些用处 就像外面那些僵尸一样
Pieces of equipment like you should just labor away and drink warm, cheap beer.
像你们这样的工具 就该每天连轴转 喝常温的廉价啤酒
Occasionally, you'll get an ice cold beer.
偶尔有幸喝到一罐冰啤酒
There's no greater happiness for you, right? Am I wrong?
你们就该喜极而泣了 对吧？我说的有错吗？
If you get it, you'll be a good little cog, stay quiet, and get back to work.
听明白了的话 就乖乖做个工具 闭上嘴回去工作吧
Got it? Damned piece of equipment.
懂了吗？没用的小工具
Did Akira seem kinda off today?
阿辉今天看起来好像不太对劲呀
I know the guy is his old boss, but why is he just taking it like that?
我知道那家伙以前是他的领导 但他干吗那么逆来顺受啊？
You never forget.
那是无法磨灭的记忆
Even if your mind knows that they're unfairly controlling you…
即使理智上明白那样不合理
Your heart never forgets
但内心却永远无法遗忘
the fear.
那种恐惧
Next time: Truck Stop of the Dead.
下一集：《死者的服务区》